A Guide to the Papers of Paul T. David
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Paul T. David
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
12793-d
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Contents List
- American Youth Commission Files 1935-1942
  - American Youth Commission- Meetings:
    - Meeting 1939 Oct 9-10 (Box 1)
    - Meeting 1940 Apr 15-16 (Box 1)
    - Meeting 1940 Jul 22-23 (Box 1)
    - --Executive Committee 1940 Sep 28 (Box 1)
    - Meeting 1940 Nov 11-12 (Box 1)
    - Meeting 1941 May 23-24 (Box 1)
    - --Executive Committee 1941 Sep 19 (Box 1)
    - Meeting 1941 Oct 8-9 (Box 1)
    - --Executive Committee 1941 Oct 8-9 (Box 1)
  - Employment Trends Study:
    - Chapter I--Long Term Economic Trends [1942] (Box 1)
    - Chapter II--Major Changes in Employment Opportunity [1941-1942] (Box 2)
    - Chapter III--Occupational Trends in Recent Decades [1940-1943] (Box 2)
    - Chapter IV--General Population Trends and Implications [1940-1943] (Box 2)
    - Chapter V--The Effects of Social Stratification [1940-1942] (Box 2)
    - Chapter VI--Trends in Agriculture [1940-1942] (Box 2)
    - Chapter VII--Migration: A Major Youth Problem [1941-1942] (Box 2)
    - Chapter VIII--Policies for the Future [1942] (Box 2)
  - General Files:
    - Galley No. 2 [n.d.] (Box 3)
    - Miscellaneous Data [1937, 1942] (Box 3)
    - Data for Charts [1942-1944] (Box 3)
    - Book [1940-1942] (Box 3)
    - Original of P.T. David's Study--Chapters I-IV [1941-1942] (Box 3)
    - Youth Employment and Unemployment [1941 May 10] (Box 3)
    - --Working Copy [1941-1942] (Box 3)
  - Youth and the Future:
    - Youth and the Future--Preliminary Draft [1941 Sep 8] (Box 4)
    - Documentation and Correspondence--Final Reports [1935-1941] (Box 4)
    - Notes on Sources of Factual Data [1941] (Box 4)
    - Youth and the Future--First Working Draft [1941] (Box 4)
    - Staff Memos and Drafts [1941] (Box 4)
  - A.Y.C. - Youth Employment and Unemployment:
    - Manuscripts--Checked Copies [1942] (Box 5)
    - Postwar Youth Employment--Miscellaneous Working Papers and Correspondence [1942] (Box 5)
    - --Permissions Correspondence [1942] (Box 5)
    - Minutes of Meetings--Executive Committee of A.Y.C. [1935-1940] (Box 5)
  - Youth Employment Study:
    - Budgets and Accounts [1940-1941] (Box 5)
    - Contracts and Interviews [1940] (Box 5)
    - Introduction and Front Matter [1940-1941] (Box 5)
    - Outlines [1940-1942] (Box 5)
    - Chapter I--Youth on the Threshold of Work [1941] (Box 5)
    - Chapter II--The Economic System Youth Enters (1 of 2) [1939-1941] (Box 5)
    - Chapter II--The Economic System Youth Enters (2 of 2) [1939-1941] (Box 6)
    - Chapter III--Occupational Trends in Northern America [1940-1941], 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Chapter IV--Population Trends and Work Opportunities: General [1940-1941] (Box 6)
    - --Population Trends and Work Opportunities: Rural-Urban [1941] (Box 6)
    - Chapter V--Private Control Over Employment [1941] (Box 7)
    - --Public Control Over Employment [1940-1941] (Box 7)
    - Chapter VII--Education and the Employment Process [1941], 2 folders (Box 7)
    - Chapter VIII--Government Activities to Assist Employers [1941], 2 folders (Box 8)
    - Chapter IX--Personnel Factors Affecting Employment [1941] (Box 8)
    - Chapter X--The Present Outcome [1941] (Box 8)
    - Chapter XI--Policies for the Future [1941] (Box 8)
  - Correspondence:
    - Lyle W. Spencer, Director Science Research Associates [1940-1941] (Box 8)
    - Miss Plunkett and Lyle W. Spencer [1940-1941] (Box 8)
    - Spencer Draft [1940] (Box 9)
  - Barriers Study:
    - Chapter I--What Determines Employment Opportunity for Youth n.d. (Box 9)
    - Chapter II--The Organization of Employment [1941] (Box 9)
    - Chapter III--Controls Over Entrance Into Specific Occupations [1941] (Box 9)
    - Chapter IV--Seniority, Share-the-Work, and Employment Stabilization n.d. (Box 9)
    - Chapter V--The Problem of Child Labor [1941] (Box 9)
    - Chapter VI--The Regulation of Minimum Wages [1942] (Box 9)
    - Chapter VII--The Problem of Juvenile Wage Policy [1941-1942] (Box 9)
    - Chapter VIII--Employment for Youth in the Future [1939-1942] (Box 9)
    - Director Script [1939] (Box 9)